adam@zethrae.us +1 (404) 666-9384

TL;DR

I'm a staff level engineer who has focused on iOS and has broad experience across modern app engineering stacks. I've been doing this for a while — and have had the good fortune of working with and learning from some top tier teams.

SKILLSET

Technologies: iOS, web, backend, GNU/Unix, macOS

Keywords: Swift, SwiftUI, UIKit, TypeScript, React, NodeJS, Python, Go, C++, Bash

EXPERIENCE

Unnamed Venture — Founder

01/2023—?

• Developed 'StateTree', a novel methodology for application state management.

Included Health — Staff Engineer

06/2019 - 01/2023

- Joined Grand Rounds ~1 year before its merger with Doctor on Demand.
- iOS Lead at Grand Rounds and through time at merge Included Health.
- Variously: lead for Mobile as a whole and for key full stack product initiatives.
- Contributed technical designs and code across mobile, web, and backend stacks.

Uber — Sr.2/Staff Engineer

07/2015 - 05/2019

New Mobility (Bikes, Scooters, 3rd party micromobility)

07/2018—Present

- Mobile tech lead for products which supported roughly 100 cities and 1M rides/week.
- Responsible for establishing and maintaining engineering, on-call, metrics, and monitoring best practices practices within the ~40 engineer group.
- Led the cross-org work integrating micromobility into the app's main entry points, lifting first rides by ~20%.

Mobile Platform, iOS Driver Organization, iOS 01/2017—06/2018 07/2015—12/2016

Driver Organization, 105

05/2014—06/2015

iOS and Python work on social apps featured by Apple and Facebook.

Amazon AWS Web Browser Engineer

09/2012 - 02/2014

C++ engineering on Amazon Silk. Building interfaces into the Chromium Content API to exposed functionality like incognito profiles, prerendering, and resource prefetching.

EDUCATION

Brown University A.B. Computer Science

Sparks Labs (Greylock), iOS + Backend Engineer

2008 - 2012

Head TA / Course Design: CS4 (Scientific Computing), CS 132 (Web Development) TA work: CS15 (Intro to OOP), CS31 (Systems), CS180 (Cybersecurity Policy) Extracurricular: Varsity Fencing